Now we can only trust them
现在只能相信他们了
Your Highness
殿下
The western neighbor seems to be moving
西边邻国疑有动作
How can Your Highness suppress this news
殿下如何能压着消息
And not let His Majesty recall troops to defend
不让陛下收兵回防
Minister Xue
薛大人
Father has planned this battle for half his life
父皇为此战筹谋半生
You have no solid evidence
大人没有真凭实据
How can I issue such an order?
叫我如何下这样的令
We're not afraid of the unlikely
咱们不怕一万
But the one in ten thousand, Your Highness
就怕万一啊殿下
If we wait for solid evidence before sending troops
发兵这等事情要是等来真凭实据
Wouldn't it be too late?
那不是什么都晚了
Your Highness is considerate of the Emperor
殿下是体谅皇上
But now the country's defenses are empty
可如今国内守备空虚
If the enemy truly invades
若真敌军犯境
And we suffer defeat
吃个败仗
Will His Majesty be considerate of Your Highness?
陛下可会体谅殿下
There were heavy rains in the southern border
南疆下了几场大雨
Which reduced your embezzlement by a bit
让大人少了吃两分油水
So you can't do this job anymore?
这差事就干不得了
Minister Xue, do you think I'm young and easy to bully
薛大人是觉得我年少可欺
And know nothing?
什么都不知情吗
Your Highness, everything I do is for Great Xuan
殿下 臣一切皆为大宣
Your servant is willing to remonstrate with death
臣愿以死进谏
Minister Xue, you mustn't
薛大人使不得啊
Your Highness
殿下
We cannot treat Great Xuan's fate as a game
不能以大宣国祚儿戏啊
Lady Chen, what brings you here?
陈夫人这是来做什么
Since Minister Xue wants to remonstrate with death
薛大人既要死谏
Go help him
去帮帮他
Yes
是
Chen Wan'er
陈婉儿
You
你
You dare kill a senior minister in the Taiji Hall
你敢在太极殿上擅杀重臣
Do you really think His Majesty will tolerate you later?
你真以为陛下以后能容你
Whether he tolerates me
能不能容
Is a matter between His Majesty and me as husband and wife
是我与陛下夫妻间的事儿
You're old
老爷子一把年纪了
Still so nosy
还这么好打听啊
The Crown Prince is overseeing the court
皇长子在朝坐镇
His Majesty is personally leading the campaign
陛下更是御驾亲征
My son has the courage to fight on the front lines
本宫的儿子尚有胆魄在前线血战
The Chen family is not panicking
陈家没慌
Gentlemen
诸位
What are you panicking about?
慌什么
The decisive battle between Great Xuan and Wuzhao
大宣与邬伖的决战
Is in these few days
就在这几日
You gentlemen shall stay in the palace as guests
诸位便暂且客宿宫中
I will personally host you
由本宫亲自招待
Before the battle is settled
战事落定之前
Anyone who passes through this gate
凡过此门者
Kill
杀
Those who speak cunningly of retreat
狡言思退者
Those who harm the state for personal gain
以私误国者
Kill
杀
Yes
是
Raise my royal banner in the formation
把朕的王旗立到阵中
Send all the imperial guard
将亲卫营都派过去
Today
今日
We must not let him escape
务必不能放其离去
Yes
是
Imperial Guard
亲卫营
Follow me and kill
随我杀
Kill
杀
Sikong Yao
司空耀
Today is the life-and-death battle between you and me
今日 便是你我生死之役
Report
报
My King
王上
Something's wrong
不好了
Xuan troops are attacking from behind
有宣军从后方袭来
Cutting off our retreat
断了我军后路
What?
什么
Follow me to cut off their retreat
随我断了他们后路
Brother
弟弟
Let's retreat
俺们撤了吧
I fell into an ambush
是俺中了埋伏
This time, I fell into an ambush
这一次 是俺中了埋伏
Let's regroup
咱们重振旗鼓
Brother
弟弟
If not for you, for your son
若不是你为了你那儿子
Not following my orders
不听俺号令
And engaging the enemy on your own
私自迎敌
How could we have come to this today?
今日何至于此
Brother
弟弟
Don't
别
My empire was destroyed by you
俺之霸业 毁于你手
Brother
弟弟
Recall the vanguard
把前军调回来
Break through from the rear
从后方突围
Yes
是